很久很久以前 有一个美丽的公主
[ Man ] ''Once upon a time there was a lovely princess.
她被一个可怕的妖术所诅咒
''But she had an enchantment upon her of a fearful sort...
只有爱人的第一个吻 才能够解除它
''which could only be broken by love's first kiss.
她被锁在一个城堡里
''She was locked away in a castle...
由一条可怕的喷火龙看守着
''guarded by a terrible fire-breathing dragon.
许多勇敢的骑士 都试图把她救出来
''Many brave knights had attempted to free her from this dreadful prison,
但没有一个成功的
''but none prevailed.
她在最高塔楼最高的房间里
''She waited in the dragon's keep...
在龙的看守下等待着
''in the highest room of the tallest tower...
“她真正的爱 和真正爱人的第一个吻”
for her true love and true love's first kiss. ''
就像真的一样，一派...
Like that's ever gonna happen.ling, - What a load of--
∮ Somebody once told me the world is gonna roll me ∮
∮ I ain't the sharpest tool in the shed ∮
∮ She was lookin'kind of dumb with her finger and her thumb ∮
∮ In the shape of an ''L '' on her forehead ∮
∮ The years start comin' and they don't stop comin'∮
∮ Fed to the rules and I hit the ground runnin'∮
∮ Didn't make sense not to live for fun ∮
∮ Your brain gets smart but your head gets dumb ∮
∮ So much to do So much to see ∮
∮ So what's wrong with takin'the backstreets ∮
∮ You'll never know if you don't go ∮
∮ You'll never shine if you don't glow ∮
∮ Hey, now You're an all-star∮
∮ Get your game on, go play ∮
∮ Hey, now,you're a rock star Get the show on, get paid ∮
∮ And all that glitters is gold ∮
∮ Only shootin'stars break the mold ∮
∮ It's a cool place and they say it gets colder∮
∮ You're bundled up now but wait till you get older∮
∮ But the meteor men beg to differ∮
∮Judging by the hole in the satellite picture ∮
∮ The ice we skate is gettin'pretty thin ∮
∮ The water's getting warm so you might as well swim ∮
∮ My world's on fire How 'bout yours ∮
注意―妖怪
∮ That's the way I like it and I'll never get bored ∮
征招：妖怪―有奖
-∮ Hey, now,you're an all-star∮ - [ Shouting ]
∮ Get your game on, go play ∮
∮ Hey, now,you're a rock star Get the show on, get paid ∮
∮ And all that glitters is gold ∮
∮ Only shootin'stars break the mold ∮
走
- Go! - Go!
- [ Record Scratching ] - Go. Go. Go.
∮ Hey, now You're an all-star∮
切勿靠近
∮ Get your game on, go play ∮
∮ Hey, now,you're a rock star Get the show on, get paid ∮
∮ And all that glitters is gold ∮
∮ Only shootin'stars break the mold ∮∮
- 你看它在里面吗？ - 来，我们来捉它！
- Think it's in there? - All right. Let's get it!
等等，你知道那个东西 会把你怎么样吗？
Whoa. Hold on. Do you know what that thing can do to you?
它会把你的骨头碾碎夹面包吃
Yeah, it'll grind your bones for its bread.
啊，实际上 那是巨兽，妖怪更坏
[ Laughs ] Yes, well, actually, that would be a giant. Now, ogres-- They're much worse.
他们会剥了你们的皮做衣服穿
They'll make a suit from your freshly peeled skin.
他们会割了你们的肝 挤出你们的眼液！
- No! - They'll shave your liver. Squeeze the jelly from your eyes!
- 涂在面包上吃很不错 - 野兽！后退，我警告你！
- Actually, it's quite good on toast. - Back! Back, beast! Back! I warn ya!
好
- [ Gasping ] - Right.
现在你们该逃跑了
[ Whispers ] This is the part where you run away.
别再回来！
And stay out!
征招神话故事人物
''Wanted. Fairy tale creatures.''
这个满了
[ Man's Voice ] All right. This one's full.
拉走
- Take it away! - [ Gasps ]
快走，快！起来！下一个？
- Move it along. Come on! Get up! - Next!
给我！你飞行的日子结束了
Give me that! Your flying days are over.
这个巫婆二十块大洋 下一个！
That's 20 pieces of silver for the witch. Next!
- 起来，快 - 只有二十块
- Get up! Come on! - Twenty pieces.
那边儿坐下！安静！
- [ Thudding ] - Sit down there! - Keep quiet!
笼子太小了
This cage is too small.
请别卖我，我不再倔了 再给我一次机会吧！
Please don't turn me in. I'll never be stubborn again. I can change. Please! Give me another chance!
- 住嘴！ - 下一个
- Oh, shut up. - Oh! - Next!
- 你有什么？ - 这个小木偶
- What have you got? - This little wooden puppet.
我不是木偶，我是个真男孩
I'm not a puppet. I'm a real boy.
这个疯玩具二十先令，拿走
Five shillings for the possessed toy.
- 别让他们带我走！ - 下一个，你有什么？
- Take it away. - Father, please! Don't let them do this! - Help me! - Next. What have you got?
我有头会说话的驴
- Well, I've got a talking donkey. - [ Grunts ]
好，如果你能证明的话 可以给你十先令
Right. Well, that's good for ten shillings, if you can prove it.
说吧，小家伙
Oh, go ahead, little fella.
- 嗯？ - 他有点儿紧张
Well? Oh, oh, he's just-- He's just a little nervous.
他真的是个话篓子 说啊，你这个笨蛋傻瓜
He's really quite a chatterbox. Talk, you boneheaded dolt--
- 我听够了，卫兵！ - 不，他会说话！他会
-That's it. I've heard enough. Guards! - No, no, he talks!
我会说话，我喜欢说话
He does. I can talk. I love to talk.
我是你见到的最爱说话的东西
I'm the talkingest damn thing you ever saw.
- 把她拖走 - 不，不！他会说话！
- Get her out of my sight. - No, no! I swear! Oh! He can talk!
- 我会飞！ - 他会飞！
Hey! I can fly! - He can fly! - He can fly!
- 他会说话！ - 是的，傻瓜！
- He can talk! - Ha, ha! That's right, fool!
我是头会飞、会说话的驴
Now I'm a flying, talking donkey.
你可能见过家蝇飞 也许甚至见过超人飞
You might have seen a housefly, maybe even a superfly,
但你从没见过驴飞
but I bet you ain't never seen a donkey fly. Ha, ha!
抓住他！
[ Grunts ] Seize him!
去追！他要跑掉了！
After him! He's getting away!
抓住！这边儿！转弯！
[ Man ] Get him! This way! Turn!
你！妖怪！
You there. Ogre! Aye?
按照法阔德勋爵的命令 我奉命逮捕你们两人
By the order of Lord Farquaad, I am authorized to place you both under arrest...
把你们送到指定的地点
and transport you to a designated... resettlement facility.
真的？你的兵在哪里？
Oh, really? You and what army?
我能跟你说句话吗？
Can I say something to you?
你真是个人物，了不起！
Listen, you was really, really somethin' back there. Incredible!
你在跟...我说话吗？
Are you talkin' to-- me? Whoa!
是的，我告诉你 你真伟大，那些卫兵
Yes, I was talkin' to you. Can I tell you that you was great back there? Those guards!
他们以为自己很棒
They thought they was all of that. Then you showed up, and bam!
他们仓惶逃脱！ 见到他们那样我真高兴
They was trippin' over themselves like babes in the woods. That really made me feel good to see that.
- 那很好，真的 - 自由的滋味真好
- Oh, that's great. Really. - Man, it's good to be free.
为什么你不跟你朋友 一起庆祝你的自由呢？
Now, why don't you go celebrate your freedom with your own friends? Hmm?
我没有朋友 我自己也不想去那里
But, uh, I don't have any friends. And I'm not goin' out there by myself.
等等！我有个好主意！ 我跟着你！
Hey, wait a minute! I got a great idea! I'll stick with you.
你是个难对付的绿战斗武器 我们能吓死任何人！
You're a mean, green, fightin' machine. Together we'll scare the spit out of anybody that crosses us.
这很可怕，如果这不起作用 你的呼吸会起作用的
Oh, wow! That was really scary. If you don't mind me sayin；
if that don't work,your breath certainly will get the job done,
你需要些口香糖 你喘气太臭了！
'cause you definitely need some Tic Tacs or something, 'cause your breath stinks!
你几乎把我的鼻毛 都烧着了，就像那次...
You almost burned the hair outta my nose, just like the time-- [ Mumbling ]
...烂草莓，我那天放了很多屁
Then I ate some rotten berries. I had strong gases eking out of my butt that day.
- 你为什么跟着我？ - 我告诉你为什么
Why are you following me? I'll tell you why.
因为我很孤独 这里除了我没有别人
∮ 'Cause I'm all alone ∮ ∮ There's no one here beside me ∮
我的问题全没了 没有人嘲笑我了
? My problems have all gone ? ∮ There's no one to deride me ∮
但你得有朋友...
∮ But you gotta have friends-- ∮
别唱了！怪不得你没有朋友
Stop singing! It's no wonder you don't have any friends.
只有真正的朋友才会这么诚实
Wow. Only a true friend would be that cruelly honest.
听着，小驴 看看我，我是谁？
Listen, little donkey. Take a look at me. What am I?
- 真高？ - 不！我是个妖怪
- Really tall? - No! I'm an ogre.
“拿着你的火把和草杈！” 这不让你烦恼吗？
You know. ''Grab your torch and pitchforks.'' Doesn't that bother you?
不
Nope.
- 真的？ - 真的，真的
- Really? - Really, really.
- 我喜欢你，你叫什么？ - 史莱克
- Oh. - Man, I like you. What's your name? Uh, Shrek.
史莱克？知道我喜欢你什么？
Shrek? Well, you know what I like about you, Shrek?
“我不在乎别人怎么看我”
You got that kind of I-don't-care-what-nobody- thinks-of-me thing.
我喜欢这个，我敬佩这个 史莱克，你没事
I like that. I respect that, Shrek. You all right.
瞧那里！谁想住在那里？
Whoo! Look at that. Who'd want to live in a place like that?
那是我的家
That would be my home.
很好！很漂亮 你是个相当不错的装璜家
Oh! And it is lovely! Just beautiful.
在预算有限的情况下 你所干的令人惊叹
You are quite a decorator. It's amazing what you've done with such a modest budget.
我喜欢那块石头 那是块不错的石头
I like that boulder. That is a nice boulder.
别靠近―注意：妖怪
- 我猜想你不常有客人 - 我喜欢一个人呆着
I guess you don't entertain much, do you? I like my privacy.
这是我们的另一个共同点
You know, I do too. That's another thing we have in common.
我讨厌有人来
Like, I hate it when you got somebody in your face.
来了就不肯走，尴尬的沉默
You're trying to give them a hint, and they won't leave. There's that awkward silence.
- 我跟你住可以吗？ - 什么？
- Can I stay with you? - Uh, what?
- 让我跟你- 起住，好吗？ - 当然！
Can I stay with you, please? - Of course! - Really?
- 真的？ - 不
- No. - Please!
我不想回去！
I don't wanna go back there!
你不知道怪物的生活 是什么样的，也许你知道
You don't know what it's like to be considered a freak. Well, maybe you do.
这就是为什么我们要在一起 让我留下吧！
But that's why we gotta stick together. You gotta let me stay! - Please! Please! - Okay! Okay!
- 好，但只能呆一晚上 - 谢谢！
- But one night only. - Ah! Thank you!
这将会很有趣！ 我们晚点儿睡，一起讲故事
- What are you-- No! No! - This is gonna be fun! We can stay up late, swappin' manly stories,
早上我做华夫饼
and in the mornin' I'm makin' waffles.
- 我在哪里睡？ - 外头！
- Oh! - Where do, uh, I sleep? Outside!
这很潇洒，我不了解你 你不了解我
Oh, well, I guess that's cool. I mean, I don't know you, and you don't know me,
因此我想外头最好
so I guess outside is best, you know.
我走了
[ Sniffles ] Here I go.
晚安
Good night. [ Sighs ]
我确实喜欢在外头 我是驴，生来就喜欢外头
I mean, I do like the outdoors. I'm a donkey. I was born outside.
只有我一个人在外头 一个人，在外头
I'll just be sitting by myself outside, I guess,you know. By myself, outside.
只有我一个人 这里除了我没有别人
? I'm all alone There's no one here beside me ?
- 我不是告诉你呆在外头吗？ - 我是在外头
[ Sighs ] I thought I told you to stay outside. - I am outside. - [ Clattering ]
这比农场差远了 不过还有什么办法呢？
Well, gents, it's a far cry from the farm, but what choice do we have?
这不是家，但还算不错
It's not home, but it'll do just fine.
多好的床
What a lovely bed.
-抓到了 - 我找到了些奶酪
- Got ya. - [ Sniffs ] I found some cheese.
真恶心！
- Ow! [ Grunts ] - Blah! Awful stuff.
- 是你吗，戈德？ - 你怎么知道是我？
- Is that you, Gorder? - How did you know?
够了！你在我的房子里干嘛？
Enough! What are you doing in my house? [ Grunts ] Hey!
不，不，不！
- [ Snickers ] - Oh, no, no, no.
死女人不能放在桌子上  但床已经被占了！
- Dead broad off the table. - Where are we supposed to put her? The bed's taken.
什么？
[ Male Voice ] What?
我住在沼泽地里，我出告示 我，我是个可怕的妖怪！
I live in a swamp. I put up signs. I'm a terrifying ogre!
我怎么才能有点儿隐私呢？
What do I have to do to get a little privacy?
不...不！
- Aah! - Oh, no. Oh, no.
不！不！
- No! No!
- 什么？ - 停下，别推
- [ Cackling Continues ] - What? - Quit it. - Don't push.
你们在我的沼泽地里干什么？
What are you doing in my swamp? [ Echoing ] Swamp! Swamp! Swamp!
哦，亲爱的
- Oh, dear!
好，出去 你们都出去，都走开！
All right, get out of here. All of you, move it! Come on! Let's go! Hapaya! Hapaya! Hey!
- 快点儿，快！ - 不，不是那里，不是那里
- Quickly. Come on! - No, no! No, no. Not there. Not there.
别看我，我没有邀请他们
Hey, don't look at me. I didn't invite them.
- 天哪，没人邀请我们 - 什么？
Oh, gosh, no one invited us.
- 我们被迫来到这里 - 谁强迫你们？
- What? - We were forced to come here.
法阔德勋爵 他连吹带唬，签署了搬迁布告
- By who? - Lord Farquaad. He huffed und he puffed und he... signed an eviction notice.
听着，有人知道法阔德 现在在哪里吗？
[ Sighs ] All right. Who knows where this Farquaad guy is?
我知道他在哪里
- [ Murmuring ] - Oh, I do. I know where he is.
还有人知道 在哪里能找到他吗？
Does anyone else know where to find him?
- 没人知道？ - 我知道！
- Anyone at all? - Me! Me!
- 谁知道？ - 选择我！
- Anyone? - Oh! Oh, pick me!
- 我知道！我知道！我！ - 好
Oh, I know! I know! Me, me! [ Sighs ] Okay, fine.
注意，所有的神话故事人物
Attention, all fairy tale things.
别再享受了 欢迎已经正式结束了
Do not get comfortable. Your welcome is officially worn out.
实际上，我马上就要 去见法阔德这个家伙
In fact, I'm gonna see this guy Farquaad right now...
把你们从我的地里赶走 哪来哪去！
and get you all off my land and back where you came from!
- 你！你跟我来 - 这正是我喜欢听到的
Oh! You! You're comin' with me. All right, that's what I like to hear, man.
史莱克和驴，两个朋友 一起去冒大险，我喜欢？
Shrek and Donkey, two stalwart friends, off on a whirlwind big-city adventure. I love it!
又上路了... 史莱克，跟我唱歌
- y On the road again y Sing it with me, Shrek. - Hey. Oh, oh!
我急不可待要上路了...
y I can't wait to get on the road again y
我刚才说你什么了？
What did I say about singing?
- 我可以吹口哨儿，哼歌吗？ - 行，哼吧
- Can I whistle? - No. - Can I hum it? - All right, hum it.
够了，他要开口了
That's enough. He's ready to talk.
跑，跑，赶快跑
Run, run, run, as fast as you can.
你抓不到我，我是个姜饼人！
You can't catch me. I'm the gingerbread man!
- 你是个魔鬼 - 我不是，你是
- You're a monster. - I'm not the monster here. You are.
你和其他的神话故事垃圾 毒坏了我完美的世界
You and the rest of that fairy tale trash, poisoning my perfect world.
- 他们都到哪里去了？ - 吃我！
Now, tell me! Where are the others? - Eat me! - [ Grunts ]
我设法公平地对待 你们这些动物
I've tried to be fair to you creatures.
现在，我的耐心消失了？ 告诉我，不然...
Now my patience has reached its end! Tell me or I'll--
- 不，别动我的糖浆扣子！ - 谁把他们藏起来了？
No, no, not the buttons. Not my gumdrop buttons. All right then. Who's hiding them?
好，我告诉你 你知道松饼人吗？
Okay, I'll tell you. Do you know the muffin man?
- 松饼人？ - 松饼人
- The muffin man? - The muffin man.
对，我知道松饼人 她住在朱瑞街？
Yes, I know the muffin man, who lives on Drury Lane?
她跟松饼人结婚了
Well, she's married to the muffin man.
- 松饼人？ - 松饼人！
- The muffin man? - The muffin man!
- 她跟松饼人结婚了 - 主人！我们找到了？
- She's married to the muffin man. - [ Door Opens ] My lord! We found it.
你还等什么？把它拿进来
Then what are you waiting for? Bring it in.
- 魔镜... - 别告诉他！别！
- Magic mirror-- - Don't tell him anything! No!
晚安，镜子，镜子 墙上的镜子
- [ Gingerbread Man Whimpers ] - Evening. Mirror, mirror, on the wall.
这不是最完美的王国吗？
Is this not the most perfect kingdom of them all?
-严格地讲你不是国王 - 西龙涅斯
Well, technically you're not a king. Uh, Thelonius.
- 你说什么？ - 我说你还不是国王
- You were saying? - What I mean is, you're not a king yet.
但你可以成为国王 你只要和公主结婚就行了
But you can become one. All you have to do is marry a princess.
接着说
- Go on. - [ Chuckles ]
那么，放松坐下吧，勋爵大人
So,just sit back and relax, my lord,
因为你就要会见 当今最合格的单身女了
because it's time for you to meet today's eligible bachelorettes.
她们来了！
And here they are!
一号倍受精神折磨 她被关在遥远的王国
Bachelorette number one is a mentally abused shut-in from a kingdom far, far away.
她喜欢吃寿司和洗热水浴
She likes sushi and hot tubbing anytime.
她的爱好还包括 为她的两个坏姐姐清理卫生
Her hobbies include cooking and cleaning for her two evil sisters.
请大家欢迎灰姑娘！
Please welcome Cinderella.
二号是位身穿斗篷的姑娘 她来自奇妙的国土
Bachelorette number two is a cape-wearing girl from the land of fancy.
她与七个男人一起生活 但她很不简单
Although she lives with seven other men, she's not easy.
吻她冰凉的嘴唇 看看她的激情有多么强烈
Just kiss her dead, frozen lips and find out what a live wire she is.
快来为白雪公主鼓掌吧！
Come on. Give it up for Snow White!
最后，但当然不是最差的
And last, but certainly not least,
一位来自火山浆围绕城堡 被龙看守的红头发姑娘
bachelorette number three is a fiery redhead from a dragon-guarded castle surrounded by hot boiling lava!
但别因此而灰心
But don't let that cool you off.
她是个上了膛的手枪 喜欢喝皮钠一可拉达
She's a loaded pistol who likes pina coladas and getting caught in the rain.
你去救她，菲奥娜公主
Yours for the rescuing, Princess Fiona!
是一号单身女？
So will it be bachelorette number one,
二号单身女 还是三号单身女？
bachelorette number two or bachelorette number three?
一二号！三号！ 一三号！
- Two! Two! - Three! Three!
一二号！ 一三？一？三？
- Two! Two! - Three! Three? One? [ Shudders ] Three?
- 选三号吧，主人！ - 好，好，三号！
Three! Pick number three, my lord! Okay, okay, uh, number three!
法阔德勋爵 你挑选了菲奥娜公主
Lord Farquaad, you've chosen Princess Fiona.
? If you like pina coladas ?
菲奥娜公主十全十美
-? And getting caught in the rain ? - Princess Fiona. -? If you're not into yoga ?? - She's perfect.
我只想找一个能够...
All I have to do is just find someone who can go--
我应该说一下儿晚上的事...
But I probably should mention the little thing that happens at night.
- 我会跟她结婚的 - 日落后...
- I'll do it. - Yes, but after sunset--
安静！我要让 菲奥娜公主成为王后
Silence! I will make this Princess Fiona my queen,
达罗克最终将有一个 十全十美的国王
and DuLoc will finally have the perfect king!
队长，集合你最好的兵 我们就要举行比武大会了
Captain, assemble your finest men. We're going to have a tournament.
你停在兰斯洛特
就在那里，那是达罗克 我说过我会找到的
But that's it. That's it right there. That's DuLoc. I told ya I'd find it.
那么，那一定 是法阔德勋爵的城堡了
So, that must be Lord Farquaad's castle.
就是那里
[ Donkey ] Uh-huh. That's the place.
你看他是不是在弥补什么？
Do you think maybe he's compensating for something? [ Laughs ]
等等！等一下儿，史莱克
Hey, wait. Wait up, Shrek.
快点儿，宝贝儿，我们晚了
Hurry, darling. We're late. Hurry.
嘿，你！
- Hey, you! - [ Screams ]
等等，我不会吃掉你的 我只是...我只...
Wait a second. Look, I'm not gonna eat ya. - I just-- I just-- - [ Whimpering ]
很安静
It's quiet.
太安静了
Too quiet.
一人都到哪里去了？ 一你看看这个！
- Where is everybody? - Hey, look at this!
通告   拉
欢迎你到完美的达罗克市来
[ Clicking Quickens ] y Welcome to DuLoc such a perfect town y
我们这里有几条规矩 现在把它们告诉你
y Here we have some rules Let us lay them down y
别惹麻烦，队伍要整齐 我们就能安然相处
? Don't make waves, stay in line and we'll get along fine ?
达罗克是个完美的地方
y DuLoc is a perfect place y
请勿践踏草地 擦亮你的皮鞋，洗净你的...脸
y Please keep off of the grass Shine your shoes, wipe your... face y
达罗克，达罗克
y DuLoc is, DuLoc is y
达罗克是个完美的地方
y DuLoc is a perfect y - y Place yy - [ Camera Shutter Clicks ]
欢迎到达罗克来
- 我们再来一遍！ - 不，不，不，不！
Wow! Let's do that again! No. No. No, no, no! No.
勇敢的骑士，你们是世界上 最优秀、最聪明的人
Brave knights. - You are the best and brightest in all the land. -??
今天，你们中的一个将证明...
Today one of you shall prove himself--
- 你想挨揍？ - 对不起
All right. You're going the right way for a smacked bottom. - Sorry about that. - [ Cheering ]
冠军将得到荣誉，不，特权
That champion shall have the honor-- no, no-- the privilege...
去从龙严密的看守中
to go forth and rescue the lovely Princess Fiona...
救出可爱的菲奥娜公主
from the fiery keep of the dragon.
如果由于什么原因 冠军没有成功
If for any reason the winner is unsuccessful,
亚军将接着去完成
the first runner-up will take his place...
如此类推...
and so on and so forth.
你们中间有些人可能会死 但这是我愿意做出的牺牲
Some of you may die, but it's a sacrifice I am willing to make.
掌声
比武现在开始！
Let the tournament begin!
那是什么？
- What is that? - [ Gasping ]
- 真丑死人了！ - 这可不怎么样
- It's hideous! - Ah, that's not very nice.
- 不过是头驴 - 是啊，骑士们，新计划！
- It's just a donkey. - Huh? Indeed. Knights, new plan!
杀死那个妖怪的人 将被授予冠军！进攻！
The one who kills the ogre will be named champion! Have at him!
-抓住他！ - 现在，快！等等...
- Get him! - Oh, hey! Now come on! Hang on now.
去！抓住他！
[ Woman ] Go ahead! Get him!
我们可以喝酒解决吗？
Can't we just settle this over a pint?
- 杀死这个野兽！ - 不？那么，好吧
[ Man ] Kill the beast! No? All right then.
来吧！
Come on!
∮ I don't give a damn about my reputation ∮
-∮ You're living in the past It's a new generation ∮ - Damn!
- [ Whinnying ] -∮ A girl can do what she wants to do ∮
∮ And that's what I'm gonna do ∮
∮ And I don't give a damn about my bad reputation ∮
∮ Oh, no, no, no, no, no Not me ∮
让我来！
-∮ Me, me, me ∮ - Hey, Shrek, tag me! Tag me!
∮ And I don't give a damn about my reputation ∮
∮ Never said I wanted to improve my station ∮
-∮ And I'm always feelin'good when I'm having fun ∮ - Yeah!
∮ And I don't have to please no one ∮
给他坐电椅！
The chair! Give him the chair!
∮ And I don't give a damn about my bad reputation ∮
∮ Oh, no, no, no, no, no Not me ∮
∮ Me, me, me ∮
∮ Oh, no, no, no, no ∮
∮ Not me, not me ∮
-∮ Not me ∮∮
谢谢！十分感谢！ 我一直呆到周四，尝尝牛肉！
Thank you! Thank you very much! I'm here till Thursday. Try the veal! Ha, ha!
- 我可以下命令吗，先生？ - 不，我有个更好的主意
Shall I give the order, sir? No, I have a better idea.
达罗克的人们 他就是我们的冠军！
People of DuLoc, I give you our champion!
- 什么？ - 祝贺你，妖怪
- What? - Congratulations, ogre.
你赢得了从事一个 伟大、高尚的探险荣誉
You've won the honor of embarking on a great and noble quest.
探求？我正在探求 寻求归还我的沼泽地
Quest? I'm already on a quest, a quest to get my swamp back.
- 你的沼泽地？ - 对，我的沼泽地！
- Your swamp? - Yeah, my swamp!
你把那些家伙扔在那里！
Where you dumped those fairy tale creatures!
是的，妖怪，我们做个交易
- [ Crowd Murmuring ] - Indeed. All right, ogre, I'll make you a deal.
你为我去探险 我就把沼泽地还给你
Go on this quest for me, and I'll give you your swamp back.
恢复原状？
Exactly the way it was?
恢复到黏泥覆盖的原始模样
Down to the last slime-covered toadstool.
- 那些擅自占据者呢？ - 全部搬走
- And the squatters? - As good as gone.
什么样的探险？
What kind of quest?
你要去跟龙作战 救出公主，然后回到沼泽地去
Let me get this straight. You're gonna go fight a dragon...
and rescue a princess just so Farquaad will give you back a swamp...
你现在没有沼泽地了 因为法阔德塞了些怪物进去
which you only don't have because he filled it full of freaks in the first place.
也许驴不会讲话是有道理的
- Is that about right? - Maybe there's a good reason donkeys shouldn't talk.
你为什么不把你的魔力 都用在他身上？
I don't get it. Why don't you just pull some of that ogre stuff on him?
包围他的堡垒
Throttle him, lay siege to his fortress,
碾碎他的骨头夹面包吃 妖怪所有的本事
grind his bones to make your bread, the whole ogre trip.
也许我可以砍掉全村人的头
Oh, I know what. Maybe I could have decapitated an entire village...
把他们挂在长矛上
and put their heads on a pike,
拿把刀，割开他们的脾 喝他们的脾液
gotten a knife, cut open their spleen and drink their fluids.
- 你看怎么样？ - 不，真的，不怎么样
Does that sound good to you? Uh, no, not really, no.
告诉你 妖怪比你想像的复杂
For your information, there's a lot more to ogres than people think.
- 举个例子 - 例子？好...
- Example? - Example?
妖怪就像洋葱
- Okay, um, ogres are like onions.
- 它们辣臭？让你流泪？ - 不！
-  They stink?- Yes-- No! - They make you cry? - No!
你把它们放在阳光下 它们都会变黄？
You leave them out in the sun, they get all brown, start sproutin' little white hairs.
是层！洋葱有好多层
No! Layers! Onions have layers.
妖怪多层！洋葱多层
Ogres have layers! Onions have layers.
你明白吗？我们都有好多层
You get it? We both have layers. [ Sighs ]
你们都有好多层 可并不是人人都喜欢洋葱
Oh, you both have layers. Oh. [ Sniffs ] You know, not everybody likes onions.
- 蛋糕！大家都喜欢蛋糕！ - 我不管...大家喜欢什么
Cake! Everybody loves cakes! Cakes have layers. I don't care... what everyone likes.
妖怪不像蛋糕
Ogres are not like cakes.
你知道大家还喜欢什么？冻糕
You know what else everybody likes? Parfaits.
你从没听见一个人说 “不，我不喜欢冻糕？”
Have you ever met a person, you say, ''Let's get some parfait,'' they say, ''No, I don't like no parfait''?
没有！你这个愚蠢讨厌的驴
- Parfaits are delicious. - No! You dense, irritating, miniature beast of burden!
妖怪不像洋葱！行了吧 再见，回头见
Ogres are like onions! End of story. Bye-bye. See ya later.
冻糕也许是这个星球上 最可口的东西
Parfaits may be the most delicious thing on the whole damn planet.
我想我宁愿听你哼歌
You know, I think I preferred your humming.
你有餐巾纸吗？ 我这里一塌糊涂
Do you have a tissue or something? I'm making a mess.
冻糕这个辞让我流口水了
Just the word parfait make me start slobbering.
∮ I'm on my way from misery to happiness today ∮
∮ Uh-huh, uh-huh Uh-huh, uh-huh ∮
∮ And everything that you receive up yonder∮
∮ Is what you give to me the day I wander∮
∮ I'm on my way ∮
∮ I'm on my way ∮∮
史莱克！是你干的吗？
Ooh! Shrek! Did you do that?
你放屁之前得通知一声
You gotta warn somebody before you just crack one off. My mouth was open.
相信我，驴 如果是我，你早就熏死了
Believe me, Donkey, if it was me, you'd be dead.
- 是硫磺石.我们一定快到了 - 对，硫磺石...
[ Sniffs ] It's brimstone. - We must be getting close. - Yeah, right, brimstone.
别告诉我硫磺石 我知道我闻到了什么
Don't be talking about it's the brimstone. I know what I smell. It wasn't no brimstone.
也没有什么石头
It didn't come off no stone neither.
确实，够大的了 但看一下位置
Sure, it's big enough, but look at the location.
史莱克？记得你说过 妖怪有好多层吗？
Uh, Shrek? Uh, remember when you said ogres have layers?
我有点儿事要坦白
Well, I have a bit of a confession to make.
驴没有好多层 我们的恐惧都表现在袖子上
Donkeys don't have layers. We wear our fear right out there on our sleeves.
- 等等！驴没有袖子 - 你明白我的意思
- Wait a second. Donkeys don't have sleeves. - You know what I mean.
你不能对我说你怕高
You can't tell me you're afraid of heights.
在沸腾岩浆湖 摇晃的桥上走我不舒服
I'm just a little uncomfortable about being on a rickety bridge over a boiling lake of lava!
别怕，驴，我就在你身边 帮助和鼓励你
Come on, Donkey. I'm right here beside ya, okay? For emotional support,
我们一起来通过 一次迈一婴儿小步
we'll just tackle this thing together one little baby step at a time.
- 真的？ - 真的，真的
- Really? - Really, really.
- 这样我感觉好多了 - 往前走
- Okay, that makes me feel so much better. -Just keep moving.
- 别往下看... - 别往下看，别往下看
- And don't look down. - Okay, don't look down. Don't look down.
别往下看，往前走 别往下看
Don't look down. Keep on moving. Don't look down.
史莱克！我在往下看！ 我过不去了！请放了我吧！
Shrek! I'm lookin' down! Oh, God, I can't do this! Just let me off, please!
- 你已经走了一半了！ - 我知道那部分安全！
- But you're already halfway. - But I know that half is safe!
好，我没有时间，你回去吧
Okay, fine. I don't have time for this. You go back.
史莱克！等等！
- Shrek, no! Wait! -Just, Donkey--
- 我们交换一下儿位置 - 别这样！
- Let's have a dance then, shall we? - Don't do that!
- 对不起，别哪样？这样？ - 对，那样
Oh, I'm sorry. Do what? - Oh, this? - Yes, that!
- 对？对，就这样，好 - 不，史莱克！
Yes? Yes, do it. Okay. [ Screams ] No, Shrek!
- 不！停下！ - 你说就这样！我在这样做啊
- No! Stop it! - You said do it! I'm doin' it.
史莱克，我要死了，我要死了
I'm gonna die. I'm gonna die. Shrek, I'm gonna die.
这就行了，驴，这就行了
That'll do, Donkey. That'll do.
酷
Cool.
那么喷火的家伙在哪里？
[ Donkey ] So where is this fire-breathing pain-in-the-neck anyway?
在里面，等我们来救她
Inside, waiting for us to rescue her.
我说的是龙，史莱克
[ Chuckles ] I was talkin' about the dragon, Shrek.
- 你怕吗？ - 不怕，但...
[ Donkey Whispering ] You afraid? No, but-- Shh.
嗯，我也不怕
Oh, good. Me neither. [ Gasps ]
害怕并不是过错
'Cause there's nothin' wrong with bein' afraid.
害怕是对陌生环境的敏感反应
Fear's a sensible response to an unfamiliar situation.
陌生的危险环境 有一条喷火的龙
Unfamiliar dangerous situation, I might add. With a dragon
that breathes fire and eats knights and breathes fire,
害怕并不意味着你是胆小鬼
it sure doesn't mean you're a coward if you're a little scared.
我确信史莱克不是胆小鬼
I sure as heck ain't no coward. I know that. [ Gasps ]
驴，两件事，好吗？
Donkey, two things, okay?
闭嘴，去看看能不能找到楼梯
Shut... up. Now go over there and see if you can find any stairs.
我以为我们在找公主
Stairs? I thought we was lookin' for the princess.
她在楼上 在最高塔内最高的房间里
The princess will be up the stairs in the highest room in the tallest tower.
- 你怎么知道她在那里？ - 我从书上看到的
- What makes you think she'll be there? - I read it in a book once.
酷，你对付龙，我来对付楼梯
Cool. You handle the dragon. I'll handle the stairs.
等我找到楼梯 我也要抽它们的屁股
I'll find those stairs. I'll whip their butt too.
它们并不知道该去哪里
Those stairs won't know which way they're goin'.
我要走难走的路 别打扰我，我是爬楼梯老手
I'm gonna take drastic steps. Kick it to the curb. Don't mess with me. I'm the stair master.
我已经征服楼梯了 踏上一步就没有问题了
I've mastered the stairs. I wish I had a step right here. I'd step all over it.
至少我们知道公主在哪里 但哪里...
Well, at least we know where the princess is, but where's the--
龙？
Dragon! [ Screams ]
驴，当心！
Donkey, look out! [ Screams ]
抓住你了！
- Got ya! - [ Roars ]
你的牙齿真大
No. Oh, no. No! [ Screams ] - Oh, what large teeth you have. - [ Growls ]
我是说，闪亮的牙齿 你也许经常听人这么夸奖
I mean, white, sparkling teeth. I know you probably hear this all the time from your food,
但你一定漂白了 因为你的笑很耀眼
but you must bleach, 'cause that is one dazzling smile you got there.
我闻到了，是薄荷味吗？
Do I detect a hint of minty freshness?
你知道吗？你是条雌龙！
And you know what else? You're-- You're a girl dragon!
当然！我是说，当然你是雌龙
Oh, sure! I mean, of course you're a girl dragon.
你散发着女性的美
You're just reeking of feminine beauty.
你怎么了？ 眼里掉进东西了？
What's the matter with you? You got something in your eye? Ooh. Oh. Oh.
我真的愿意留下，但...
Man, I'd really love to stay, but, you know, I'm, uh-- [ Coughs ]
我有气喘病 如果你吐烟圈我会受不了的
I'm an asthmatic, and I don't know if it'd work out if you're gonna blow smoke rings.
史莱克
No! Shrek! Shrek!
Shrek!
- 醒醒！ - 什么？
- Wake up! - What?
你是菲奥娜公主吗？
Are you Princess Fiona?
是，我在等待 一个勇敢的骑士来救我
I am, awaiting a knight so bold as to rescue me.
很好，我们走吧！
Oh, that's nice. Now let's go!
等等，骑士先生 这是我们第一次见面
But wait, Sir Knight. This be-ith our first meeting.
这不该是一个 非常浪漫的时刻吗？
Should it not be a wonderful, romantic moment?
- 是，对不起，女士，没时间 - 你在干什么？
- Yeah, sorry, lady. There's no time. - Hey, wait. What are you doing?
你应该抱起我
You should sweep me off my feet...
冲出远处的窗户 落在你勇敢的马上
out yonder window and down a rope onto your valiant steed.
你有很多时间计划这些 是不是？
You've had a lot of time to plan this, haven't you? Mm-hmm. [ Screams, Grunts ]
但我们得品尝这个时刻！ 你该给我背段壮丽的诗
But we have to savor this moment! You could recite an epic poem for me.
叙事史诗？十四行诗！
A ballad? A sonnet!
- 五行打油诗？或是别的！ - 我并不这样认为
- A limerick? Or something! - I don't think so.
至少我该知道英雄的名字吧？
Can I at least know the name of my champion?
史莱克
Um, Shrek.
史莱克先生
Sir Shrek. [ Clears Throat ]
我祈求你把这个手帕 当作我感谢的象征
I pray that you take this favor as a token of my gratitude.
谢谢！
Thanks!
- 你没有杀死龙？ - 这在我们的计划内，来！
You didn't slay the dragon? - It's on my to-do list. Now come on! - [ Screams ]
但不该这样！
But this isn't right!
你应该像其他骑士一样 在他们被烧死前
You were meant to charge in, sword drawn, banner flying. That's what all the other knights did.
- 冲锋陷阵，挥剑拔刀 - 这不是问题所在
Yeah, right before they burst into flame. That's not the point. Oh!
你去哪里？出口在那边儿
Wait. Where are you going? The exit's over there.
- 我要救我的驴 - 你是什么骑士？
Well, I have to save my ass. What kind of knight are you?
独一无二的骑士
One of a kind.
慢点儿，慢点儿，宝贝儿
[ Donkey ] Slow down. Slow down, baby, please.
时间久了才能全面了解一个人
I believe it's healthy to get to know someone over a long period of time.
就叫我老古板吧
Just call me old-fashioned. [ Laughs ]
我不想仓促拥有肉体关系
I don't want to rush into a physical relationship.
我感情上还没有投入这...
I'm not emotionally ready for a commitment of, uh, this--
伟大是我要找的字
Magnitude really is the word I'm looking for.
伟大，这是不想要的 肉体关系，你在干什么？
Magnitude-- Hey, that is unwanted physical contact. Hey, what are you doing?
让我们回头一步一步地来
Okay, okay. Let's just back up a little and take this one step at a time.
我们真的应该 先做个朋友或者笔友
We really should get to know each other first as friends or pen pals.
我经常在路上旅行 但我喜欢接收明信片...
I'm on the road a lot, but I just love receiving cards--
我确实想留下，但...
I'd really love to stay, but--
别这样！这是我私人的尾巴
Don't do that! That's my tail! That's my personal tail.
你要去掉？你要用它做什么？
You're gonna tear it off. I don't give permission-- What are you gonna do with that?
现在！不行，不！
Hey, now. No way. No! No!
不！不！不！
No, no! No. No, no, no! No! Oh!
- 嗨，公主！ - 它会说话！
- Hi, Princess! - It talks!
对，让他闭嘴得用窍门
Yeah, it's getting him to shut up that's the trick.
好，你们俩，朝出口前进！
Okay, you two, head for the exit!
我来对付龙
I'll take care of the dragon.
跑
Run!
你成功了！你救了我！ 真令人惊叹，你...
- [ Dragon Growling In The Distance ] - You did it! You rescued me! You're amazing. You're--
你太伟大了，你是...
You're wonderful. You're...
我得承认，有点儿怪
a little unorthodox I'll admit.
但你的行为伟大，心底纯洁
But thy deed is great, and thine heart is pure.
我将永远感激你
- I am eternally in your debt. - [ Clears Throat ]
没有高贵的马 哪里有勇敢的骑士？
And where would a brave knight be without his noble steed?
我希望你听到了这些话 她说我是高贵的马！
I hope you heard that. She called me a noble steed. She think I'm a steed.
战斗打赢了 可以摘掉头盔了，好骑士先生
[ Fiona Laughs ] The battle is won. You may remove your helmet, good Sir Knight.
- 为什么不？ - 我的头发被压扁了
- Uh, no. - Why not? I have helmet hair.
求你，我想看看救我人的脸
Please. I would'st look upon the face of my rescuer.
- 不，不，你不想...
No, no, you wouldn't-- 'st.
- 可你怎么吻我？ - 这不在工作的要求里 - 也许是个奖赏
But how will you kiss me? What? That wasn't in the job description. Maybe it's a perk.
不，是命运 你一定要知道是怎么回事
No, it's destiny. Oh, you must know how it goes.
一个被关在塔楼里 由龙看守的公主
A princess locked in a tower and beset by a dragon...
被一个勇敢的骑士搭救了
is rescued by a brave knight,
然后他们分享了 真正爱人的第一个吻
and then they share true love's first kiss.
和史莱克？你想...等等 你以为他是你真正的爱人？
Hmm? With Shrek? You think-- Wait. Wait. You think that Shrek is your true love?
是啊！
Well, yes.
- 史莱克是你真正的爱人！ - 这有什么好笑的？
You think Shrek is your true love! What is so funny?
- 我不是你喜欢的那种 - 不，你是，你救了我
Let's just say I'm not your type, okay? Of course, you are. You're my rescuer.
- 现在，摘掉你的头盔 - 这不是个好主意
Now-- Now remove your helmet. Look. I really don't think this is a good idea.
- 就把头盔摘掉 - 不
-Just take off the helmet. - I'm not going to.
-摘掉，现在！ - 好！
- Take it off. - No! - Now! - Okay!
别发火，听从你的命令，阁下
Easy. As you command, Your Highness.
你...你是个妖怪
You-- You're a--an ogre.
- 你以为我像王子一样漂亮？ - 嗯，对，是这样的
Oh, you were expecting Prince Charming. Well, yes, actually.
不，都搞错了 你不应该是个妖怪
Oh, no. This is all wrong. You're not supposed to be an ogre.
公主，我是被法阔德勋爵 派来救你的
[ Sighs ] Princess, I was sent to rescue you by Lord Farquaad, okay?
- 是他想跟你结婚 - 那他为什么不来救我？
He's the one who wants to marry you. Then why didn't he come rescue me?
好问题，到那里后你去问他
Good question. You should ask him that when we get there.
但我该被真正的爱人搭救
But I have to be rescued by my true love,
而不是被妖怪和他的宠物搭救
not by some ogre and his-- his pet.
- 再也不是高贵的马了 - 你使我的工作更麻烦了
So much for noble steed. You're not making my job any easier.
对不起 你的工作不是我的问题
I'm sorry, but your job is not my problem.
你去告诉法阔德 如果他想体面地救我
You can tell Lord Farquaad that if he wants to rescue me properly,
我就在这里等他
I'll be waiting for him right here.
我不是个送信的 我是个送货的
Hey! I'm no one's messenger boy, all right? I'm a delivery boy.
- 你不敢，把我放下！ - 你来吗，驴？
You wouldn't dare. - Put me down! - Ya comin', Donkey?
我就在你后面
I'm right behind ya.
放下我，不然你将自食其果！
Put me down, or you will suffer the consequences!
这太没有尊严了！放下我！
This is not dignified! Put me down! [ Screams ]
现在又有个问题
Okay, so here's another question.
有个女人她喜欢你 但你不喜欢她
Say there's a woman that digs you, right, but you don't really like her that way.
怎么才能容易地摆脱她 而不被她烧伤吃掉呢？
How do you let her down real easy so her feelings aren't hurt, but you don't get burned to a crisp and eaten?
就告诉她 她不是你真正爱的人
You just tell her she's not your true love.
当发现了真爱时 每个人都明白会...
Everyone knowest what happens when you find your--
越早赶到达罗克越好
The sooner we get to DuLoc the better.
你会喜欢那里的 那里很美丽！
You're gonna love it there, Princess. It's beautiful!
我的未婚夫法阔德怎么样？ 他长得什么样？
And what of my groom-to-be? Lord Farquaad? What's he like?
我这样来说吧，公主
Let me put it this way, Princess.
像法阔德那样矮的人很少
Men of Farquaad's stature are in short supply.
我不知道，有人很少瞧见他
I don't know. There are those who think little of him.
停下，你俩都停下
Stop it. Stop it, both of you.
你们是在嫉妒 你们没法跟法阔德勋爵比
You're just jealous you can never measure up to a great ruler like Lord Farquaad.
对，也许你说得对，公主
Yeah, well, maybe you're right, Princess.
但明天见到他时 你最好亲自量量他
But I'll let you do the ''measuring'' when you see him tomorrow.
明天？要等那么久啊？
Tomorrow? It'll take that long?
- 我们停下露营吧？ - 不，那会更久
- Shouldn't we stop to make camp? - No, that'll take longer.
- 我们接着走吧 - 但树林林里可能有强盗
- We can keep going. - But there's robbers in the woods.
停下！露营现在听起来不错！
Whoa! Time out, Shrek! Camping's starting to sound good.
我比这个森林里 任何的东西都更可怕
Hey, come on. I'm scarier than anything we're going to see in this forest.
我要找个地方露营！
I need to find somewhere to camp now!
- 过来 - 可以找个更好的地方
- Hey! Over here. - Shrek, we can do better than that.
这不适合公主
I don't think this is fit for a princess.
很完美 再来几下家庭的润色就行了
No, no, it's perfect. It just needs a few homey touches.
家庭的润色？像什么？
- Homey touches? Like what? - [ Crashing ]
一扇门？先生，祝你们晚安
A door? Well, gentlemen, I bid thee good night.
- 睡前我给你讲个故事吧？ - 我说过晚安！
You want me to read you a bedtime story? I will. I said good night!
史莱克，你在干什么？
Shrek, what are you doing?
我只...你知道...别担心 我只是开玩笑
[ Laughs ] I just-- You know-- Oh, come on. I was just kidding.
那个，那是斯洛白克
[ Fire Crackling ] And, uh, that one, that's Throwback,
惟一吐过三块麦地的妖怪
the only ogre to ever spit over three wheat fields.
对，好
Right. Yeah.
你能看星相说出我的未来吗？
Hey, can you tell my future from these stars?
星相不能告诉我们未来 他们告诉我们故事
The stars don't tell the future, Donkey. They tell stories.
瞧，布拉纳特臭气
Look, there's Bloodnut, the Flatulent.
- 你可以猜出它为什么出名 - 你在编造
- You can guess what he's famous for. - I know you're making this up.
不，瞧，它在那里 猎人都臭跑了
No, look. There he is, and there's the group of hunters running away from his stench.
它们只是群小星星
That ain't nothin' but a bunch of little dots.
有时候事情 并不像表面上那么简单
Sometimes things are more than they appear.
算了吧
Forget it.
回到我们的沼泽地后 我们做什么？
Hey, Shrek, what we gonna do when we get our swamp anyway?
- 我们的沼泽地？ - 我们救了公主
Our swamp? You know, when we're through rescuing the princess.
我们？驴，没有“我们” 没有“我们的”
We? Donkey, there's no ''we.'' There's no ''our.''
那是我的沼泽地
There's just me and my swamp.
我要做的第一件事 就是建个十英尺高的围墙
The first thing I'm gonna do is build a ten-foot wall around my land.
你伤害了我 你刚才深深地伤害了我
You cut me deep, Shrek. You cut me real deep just now.
我想围墙只是为了堵人
You know what I think? I think this whole wall thing is just a way to keep somebody out.
不，你这么想？
- No, do ya think?
- 你在隐瞒什么？ - 没什么
- Are you hidin' something?Never mind, Donkey.
这是另一个洋葱的问题 对不对？
Oh, this is another one of those onion things, isn't it?
不，这是个“别谈了”的问题
No, this is one of those drop-it and leave-it-alone things.
- 你为什么不想谈呢？ - 你为什么想谈？
- Why don't you want to talk about it? - Why do you want to?
- 你为什么要抑制自己？ - 我没有
- Why are you blocking? - I'm not blocking.
- 你在抑制 - 我在警告你
- Oh, yes, you are. - Donkey, I'm warning you.
- 你想堵住谁？ - 每个人！行了吧？
- Who you trying to keep out? - Everyone! Okay?
- 现在我们有所进展了 - 看在圣彼得的面上！
Oh, now we're gettin' somewhere. Oh! For the love of Pete!
- 你对世界有什么不满？ - 不是我有不满
What's your problem? What you got against the whole world? I'm not the one with the problem, okay?
世界看起来对我不满
It's the world that seems to have a problem with me.
人们看我一眼说 “救命！一个大丑妖怪！”
People take one look at me and go, ''Aah! Help! Run! A big, stupid, ugly ogre!''
他们不了解我就下了结论 这就是为什么我最好一个人
[ Sighs ] They judge me before they even know me. That's why I'm better off alone.
你知道吗？我们见面时
You know what?
我没有认为你是个大丑妖怪
When we met, I didn't think you was just a big, stupid, ugly ogre.
- 对，我知道 - 那么，天上有驴吗？
Yeah, I know. So, uh, are there any donkeys up there?
嗯，有个多嘴的驴 是个讨厌的小家伙
Well, there's, um, Gabby, the Small and Annoying.
我看到了，一个闪亮的大家伙 就在那里，那边那个？
Okay, I see it now. The big shiny one, right there. That one there?
- 那是月亮 - 啊，对
- That's the moon. - Oh, okay.
再给我看看
[ Farquaad ] Again. Show me again.
镜子，镜子，让我再看看她 让我再看看公主
Mirror, mirror, show her to me. Show me the princess.
十全十美
Ah. Perfect. [ Inhales ]
对，你知道我喜欢这样 宝贝儿，我说过就喜欢这样
Mmm,yeah,you know I like it like that. - Come on, baby. I said I like it. - Donkey, wake up.
- 驴，醒醒 - 什么？
- Huh? What? - Wake up. - What? - Good morning.
史莱克，你喜欢吃啥样的蛋？
How do you like your eggs?
- 早安，公主！ - 这是怎么回事？
- Good morning, Princess! - What's all this about?
我们昨天开始得不好
We kind of got off to a bad start yesterday.
我想弥补一下儿 我是说，毕竟你救了我
I wanted to make it up to you. After all, you did rescue me.
谢谢
- Uh, thanks. - [ Sniffs ]
吃吧，今天会很忙
Well, eat up. We've got a big day ahead of us.
什么？这是赞美 我总是说出气比进气好
- [ Belches ] - Shrek! What? It's a compliment. Better out than in, I always say. [ Laughs ]
在公主面前不能这样
- Well, it's no way to behave in front of a princess. - [ Belches ]
- 谢谢 - 她和你一样粗野
- Thanks. - She's as nasty as you are.
你知道，你不像我想像的那样
[ Laughs ] You know, you're not exactly what I expected.
也许在不了解之前 不该下结论
Maybe you shouldn't judge people before you get to know them.
解放了！
[ Man ] La liberte! Hey!
公主
Princess!
你要干什么？
- [ Laughs ] - What are you doing?
别动，我亲爱的 因为我是你的救星！
Be still, mon cherie, for I am your savior!
我从这个绿...兽掌中 救出了你
And I am rescuing you from this green-- [ Kissing Sounds ] - beast. - Hey!
这是我的公主！去找你的吧！
That's my princess! Go find your own!
巨兽！ 你没看见我正忙着吗？
Please, monster! Can't you see I'm a little busy here?
瞧，伙计，我不知道你是谁...
Look, pal, I don't know who you think you are!
当然！多么粗野 我来介绍一下儿我自己
Oh! Of course! Oh, how rude. Please let me introduce myself.
伙计们！
Oh, Merry Men! [ Laughs ]
∮ Ta, dah, dah, dah, whoo ∮
打富济贫
y I steal from the rich and give to the needy y
- 他提取一成 - 但我并不贪婪
- y He takes a wee percentage y - y But I'm not greedy y
我救美人，伙计，我是好人
y I rescue pretty damsels Man, I'm good y
- 多好的伙计！鲁宾逊先生 - 开始跳吧
- y What a guy, Monsieur Hood y - Break it down.
我喜欢诚实的决斗 和漂亮的小姑娘
y I like an honest fight and a saucy little maid y
- 他在说他想得到... - 回报
- y What he's basically saying is he likes to get-- y - y Paid y
当树丛中的妖怪 抓着女士的屁股，这可不好
- y So y - y When an ogre in the bush grabs a lady by the tush y - y That's bad y - y That's bad y
美女和野兽在一起 这会让我发疯的
? When a beauty's with a beast it makes me awfully mad ?
他疯了，他真的疯了
y He's mad He's really, really mad y
我要拔出我的刀 猛刺你的心脏
y I'll take my blade and ram it through your heart y
看着我，小子们 我就要行动了
y Keep your eyes on me, boys 'cause I'm about to start yy
- 伙计，真够烦人的！ - 你这个小...
[ Panting ] Man, that was annoying! Oh, you little--
我们走吧
[ Chuckles ] Um, shall we?
等一会儿
- Hold the phone. - [ Grunts ]
- 等等，这是哪里学来的？ - 什么？
Oh! Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hold on now. - Where did that come from? - What?
刚才那个！ 令人惊叹，你是从哪里学的？
That! Back there. That was amazing! Where did you learn that?
一个人自己住时 你不得不学这些，以防...
Well-- [ Chuckles ] When one lives alone, uh, one has to learn these things in case there's a--
- 你屁股上有根箭！ - 什么？
- There's an arrow in your butt! - What?
- 你看看好吗？ - 这都是我的错
- Oh, would you look at that? - Oh, no. This is all my fault.
- 对不起 - 怎么了？
- I'm so sorry. - Why? What's wrong?
- 史莱克受伤了 - 史莱克受伤了？他要死了
- Shrek's hurt. - Shrek's hurt. Shrek's hurt? Oh, no, Shrek's gonna die.
- 驴，我没事儿 - 不！我太年轻了，你不能死
- Donkey, I'm okay. - You can't do this to me. I'm too young for you to die.
把你的脚抬起来，咳嗽！
Keep your legs elevated. Turn your head and cough.
- 有人会黑里奇疗法吗？ - 镇静！
- Does anyone know the Heimlich? - Donkey! Calm down.
如果你想帮助史莱克 去找一种带红刺的蓝花
If you want to help Shrek, run into the woods and find me a blue flower with red thorns.
蓝花，红刺 好，蓝花，红刺
Blue flower, red thorns. Okay, I'm on it. Blue flower, red thorns.
如果你看到长隧道，躲开光！
Don't die, Shrek. If you see a long tunnel, stay away from the light!
好，蓝花红刺
- [ Both ] Donkey! - Oh, yeah. Right. Blue flower, red thorns.
- 要花干什么？ - 是为了让驴走开
- Blue flower, red thorns. - What are the flowers for? - For getting rid of Donkey. - Ah.
- 别动，我给你拔出来 -轻点儿拔
Now you hold still, and I'll yank this thing out. Ow! Hey! Easy with the yankin'.
- 一定要拔出来 - 不，轻点儿
- I'm sorry, but it has to come out. - No, it's tender.
现在，坚持住...
Now, hold on.
- 没什么用 - 别动
- What you're doing is the opposite of help. - Don't move.
- 停下 - 你能...
- Look, time out. - Would you--
好，你建议我们怎么做？
[ Grunts ] Okay. What do you propose we do?
蓝花，红刺
Blue flower, red thorns. Blue flower, red thorns. Blue flower, red thorns.
如果我不是色盲就好了 蓝花...
This would be so much easier if I wasn't color-blind! - Blue flower, red thorns. - [ Shrek ] Ow!
坚持住，史莱克！我来了！
Hold on, Shrek! I'm comin'!
不好受！
Ow! Not good.
好，我几乎可以看到头了 就要...
-Okay. Okay, I can nearly see the head. -[ Grunts ] - It's just about-- - Ow! Ohh!
什么也没发生，我们正要...
Nothing happened. We were just, uh--
如果你想一个人呆着 你只须说声就行了
Look, if you wanted to be alone, all you had to do was ask.
别傻！这是我最不想干的事 公主正要...
Oh, come on! That's the last thing on my mind. The princess here was just-- Ugh!
那是什么？ 那是...是血吗？
- Ow! - Hey, what's that? [ Nervous Chuckle ] That's-- Is that blood?
∮ My beloved monster and me ∮
∮ We go everywhere together∮
∮ Wearin'a raincoat that has four sleeves ∮
-∮ Gets us through all kinds of weather∮ - Aah!
∮ She will always be the only thing ∮
∮ That comes between me and the awful sting ∮
∮ That comes from living in a world that's so damn mean ∮
∮ Oh, oh-oh-oh-oh ∮
-∮ La-la, la-la, la-la-la-la ∮ - [ Both Laughing ]
∮ La-la, la-la, la-la ∮∮
在那里，公主
There it is, Princess.
- 你的未来在等待着你 - 那是达罗克？
Your future awaits you. - That's DuLoc? - Yeah, I know.
是，史莱克认为 法阔德在弥补什么
You know, Shrek thinks Lord Farquaad's compensating for something,
我想这意味着他有个...
which I think means he has a really-- Ow!
- 我想我们最好上路吧 - 当然，但史莱克？
Um, I, uh-- - I guess we better move on. - Sure. But, Shrek?
我担心驴
- I'm-- I'm worried about Donkey. - [ Blubbering ]
- 什么？ - 我是说，你看他
- What? - I mean, look at him.
- 他看起来很不好 - 什么？我很好！
- He doesn't look so good. - What are you talking about? I'm fine.
他们总是这么说 然后他们就倒下了...
That's what they always say, and then next thing you know, you're on your back.
- 死了 - 她说得对，你气色不好
- Dead. - You know, she's right.
- 你想坐下歇会儿吗？ - 我来泡杯茶
You look awful. Do you want to sit down?
我原来不想说，我的脖子刺痛
- I'll make you some tea. - I didn't want to say nothin',
当我转动时，瞧？
but I got this twinge in my neck, and when I turn my head like this, look. - Ow! See?
- 谁饿了？我去找饭 - 我去找柴火
-Who's hungry? I'll find us some dinner. -I'll get the firewood.
你们去哪里？ 伙计，我感觉不到脚趾头了！
Hey, where you goin'? Oh, man, I can't feel my toes!
我没有脚趾头了 谁来抱抱我？！
I don't have any toes! I think I need a hug.
这个很好吃，真的
Mmm. This is good. This is really good.
- 这是什么？ - 草老鼠，是烧烤的
- What is this? - Uh, weedrat. Rotisserie style.
- 说真的，还挺香的 - 炖着吃也很香
No kidding. Well, this is delicious. Well, they're also great in stews.
我不是吹牛 我做的炖草鼠很出色
Now, I don't mean to brag, but I make a mean weedrat stew.
我想明晚的饭菜会有点儿不同
[ Sighs ] I guess I'll be dining a little differently tomorrow night.
也许某天你可以来沼泽地看我
[ Gulps ] Maybe you can come visit me in the swamp sometime.
我给你做各种饭菜
I'll cook all kinds of stuff for you.
沼泽蛤蟆汤 生鱼眼饼，你就说吧...
Swamp toad soup, fish eye tartare-- you name it.
我会喜欢的
[ Chuckles ] I'd like that.
? See the pyramids along the Nile ?
- 公主？ - 什么，史莱克？
Um, Princess? -? Watch the sunrise from a tropic isle ? - Yes, Shrek?
我在想...你...
- I, um, I was wondering. -?Just remember, darling all the while ? Are you--
? You belong to me ??
你会吃这些吗？
[ Sighs ] Are you gonna eat that?
看着日落很浪漫，是不是？
- Man, isn't this romantic? Just look at that sunset. - Sunset?
- 日落？不？我是说太晚了 - 什么？
Oh, no! I mean, it's late. - I-It's very late. - What?
等等，我明白是怎么回事了
Wait a minute. I see what's goin' on here.
你怕黑吗？
- You're afraid of the dark, aren't you? - Yes!
对，是这样！我怕黑 我最好进去
Yes, that's it. I'm terrified. You know, I'd better go inside.
没什么，我以前也怕黑
Don't feel bad, Princess. I used to be afraid of the dark, too, until--
不，等等！我仍旧怕黑
Hey, no, wait. I'm still afraid of the dark.
- 晚安 - 晚安
- [ Shrek Sighs ] - Good night. Good night.
- 我知道这里发生了什么事 - 你在说什么？
Now I really see what's goin' on here. Oh, what are you talkin' about?
我是动物，我有直觉
I don't even wanna hear it. Look, I'm an animal, and I got instincts.
我知道你俩互相爱慕
I know you two were diggin' on each other. I could feel it.
你疯了 我只是把她带给法阔德
You're crazy. I'm just bringing her back to Farquaad.
醒醒闻闻气味吧！ 去告诉她你对她的感觉
Oh, come on, Shrek. Wake up and smell the pheromones. -Just go on in and tell her how you feel. - I--
没什么好说的 再说，就是我对她说了
There's nothing to tell. Besides, even if I did tell her that,
你知道，我不是说我要去说 我不会去说的
well, you know-- and I'm not sayin' I do 'cause I don't--
- 她是公主而我是... - 妖怪？
she's a princess, and I'm-- An ogre?
对，一个妖怪
Yeah. An ogre.
- 你去哪里？ - 再去...找些柴火
- Hey, where you goin'? - To get... more firewood.
公主！菲奥娜公主？
Princess? Princess Fiona?
公主，你在哪里？
Princess, where are you?
公主
Princess?
这里怪可怕的 我不是在玩游戏
It's very spooky in here. I ain't playing no games.
- 不，不！ - 不！救命！
- Aah! - Oh, no! - No, help!
不，没事儿
- Shh! - Shrek! Shrek! Shrek! - No, it's okay. It's okay.
- 公主在哪里？ - 我就是公主
- What did you do with the princess? - Donkey, I'm the princess.
- 是我，在这个躯体里 - 天啊！你吃了公主！
- Aah! - It's me, in this body. Oh, my God! You ate the princess!
你能听见吗？保持呼吸 我把你救出来！
- Can you hear me? - Donkey! - Listen, keep breathing! I'll get you out of there! - No!
史莱克
- Shrek! Shrek! Shrek! - Shh.
这就是我
- Shrek! - This is me.
公主
Princess?
你怎么了？你...变样了
What happened to you? You're, uh, uh, uh, different.
- 我变丑了，是吗？ - 是的！
- I'm ugly, okay? - Well, yeah!
是因为你吃的东西？ 我知道不该吃那些老鼠
Was it something you ate? 'Cause I told Shrek those rats was a bad idea.
- 我说是你吃的东西 - 不
- You are what you eat, I said. Now-- - No.
我从记事起就一直这个样子
I-- I've been this way as long as I can remember.
什么？我从没见过你这个样子
What do you mean? Look, I ain't never seen you like this before.
日落后才会这样
It only happens when the sun goes down.
白天一个样，晚上一个样 这是规律
''By night one way, by day another. ''This shall be the norm...
直到得到真正爱人的初吻 然后变成他的模样
''until you find true love's first kiss... and then take love's true form.''
真美，我不知道你会写诗
Ah, that's beautiful. I didn't know you wrote poetry.
这是诅咒
It's a spell.
我小的时候 一个巫婆诅咒了我
[ Sighs ] When I was a little girl, a witch cast a spell on me.
每天晚上 我都会变成这个可怕的丑兽
Every night I become this. This horrible, ugly beast!
我被放在塔中 等待真正的爱人来救我
I was placed in a tower to await the day my true love would rescue me.
这就是为什么明天日落前 我得跟法阔德结婚
That's why I have to marry Lord Farquaad tomorrow... before the sun sets
在他见到我...像这样之前
and he sees me...like this. [ Sobs ]
好，镇静，还不是太差
All right, all right. Calm down. Look, it's not that bad.
我不会撒谎，你是丑 但不是太丑
You're not that ugly. Well, I ain't gonna lie. You are ugly.
而且你只是夜里丑 史莱克却时时如此
But you only look like this at night. Shrek's ugly 2 4-7.
但，驴，我是位公主
But, Donkey, I'm a princess,
公主不该是这个模样
and this is not how a princess is meant to look.
你不跟法兰德结婚，好吗？
Princess, how 'bout if you don't marry Farquaad?
我不得不，只有真正爱人的吻 才能解除诅咒
I have to. Only my true love's kiss can break the spell.
但，你...也算是个妖怪
But, you know, um, you're kind of an ogre,
史莱克，嗯 你们有很多的共同点
and Shrek-- well, you got a lot in common.
史莱克
Shrek?
公主，我... 首先，你好吗？
Princess, I-- Uh, how's it going, first of all?
好？对，我也好，我很好
Good? Um, good for me too. I'm okay.
我看到了这些花想到了你 因为花很漂亮...
I saw this flower and thought of you because it's pretty and--
我不怎么喜欢，但我想 你可能会，因为你很漂亮
well, I don't really like it, but I thought you might like it 'cause you're pretty.
但我仍很喜欢你，我...
But I like you anyway. I'd-- uh, uh--
我遇到麻烦了，好，走吧
I'm in trouble. Okay, here we go.
我不能随便嫁人的 看看我，驴
[ Fiona ] I can't just marry whoever I want. Take a good look at me, Donkey.
我是说，真的 谁会爱一个可怕的丑八怪？
I mean, really, who could ever love a beast so hideous and ugly?
公主和丑不相容
''Princess''and ''ugly'' don't go together.
这就是为什么我不能 跟史莱克呆在一起的原因
- That's why I can't stay here with Shrek. - [ Gasps ]
我惟一幸福生活的机会 就是跟我真正的爱人结婚
My only chance to live happily ever after is to marry my true love.
你不明白吗，驴？ 我不得不这样做
- [ Deep Sigh ] - Don't you see, Donkey? That's just how it has to be.
这是解除诅咒惟一的方法
It's the only way to break the spell.
你应该把真相告诉史莱克
- You at least gotta tell Shrek the truth. - No!
不！你不能透露一个字 不能告诉任何人
You can't breathe a word. No one must ever know.
- 如果要保密为什么告诉我？ - 你发誓不说，发誓！
What's the point of being able to talk if you gotta keep secrets? Promise you won't tell. Promise!
好，我不说，但你应该说
All right, all right. I won't tell him. But you should.
我知道在此结束之前 我需要接受治疗
I just know before this is over, I'm gonna need a whole lot of serious therapy.
瞧我的眼在抽搐
- Look at my eye twitchin'. - [ Door Opens ]
我告诉他，不告诉他
[ Fiona ] I tell him, I tell him not.
我告诉他，不告诉他 我告诉他
I tell him, I tell him not. I tell him.
史莱克
Shrek!
史莱克，有件事...
Shrek, there's something I want-- [ Snoring ]
史莱克
Shrek.
- 你没事儿吧？ - 没事儿，空前良好
- Are you all right? - Perfect! Never been better.
有件事我得告诉你
I-- I don't-- There's something I have to tell you.
你不必告诉我什么 昨晚我听得够多了！
You don't have to tell me anything, Princess. - I heard enough last night.
- 你听到我的话了？ - 每一个字
- You heard what I said?Every word.
我想你能理解
I thought you'd understand.
我理解，就像你说的那样 谁会爱一个可怕的丑兽？
Oh, I understand. Like you said, ''Who could love a hideous, ugly beast?''
我以为这对你不重要
But I thought that wouldn't matter to you.
是吗？啊，很重要
Yeah? Well, it does.
准时到达
- Ah, right on time. - [ Horse Whinnies ]
公主，我给你带来个小东西
Princess, I've brought you a little something.
我错过了什么？
[ Yawns ] What'd I miss? What'd I miss?
是谁说的？不可能是驴
[ Muffled ] Who said that? Couldn't have been a donkey.
- 菲奥娜公主 - 按照承诺，给我地契
Princess Fiona. As promised. Now hand it over.
很好，妖怪，你沼泽地的契约 按照协议已经清除好了
Very well, ogre. The deed to your swamp, cleared out, as agreed.
在我改变主意之前 拿着它走吧
Take it and go before I change my mind.
原谅我，公主 让你吃惊了，但你让我吃惊
Forgive me, Princess, for startling you, but you startled me,
我从没见过这么耀人的美
for I have never seen such a radiant beauty before.
我是法阔德勋爵
I am Lord Farquaad.
法阔德勋爵？不，不
Lord Farquaad? Oh, no, no.
请原谅，勋爵 我正要简短地...
- [ Snaps Fingers ] - Forgive me, my lord, for I was just saying...
告别
a short... farewell.
真优美 你不必对那个妖怪有礼貌
That is so sweet. You don't have to waste good manners on the ogre.
- 它不懂什么感情 - 你说得对，它不懂
It's not like it has feelings. No, you're right. It doesn't.
菲奥娜公主 美丽、洁白无无的菲奥娜
Princess Fiona, beautiful, fair, flawless Fiona.
我向你求婚
- I ask your hand in marriage. - [ Gasps ]
你愿意做完美新郎 完美的新娘吗？
Will you be the perfect bride for the perfect groom?
法阔德勋爵，我愿意 没什么比...
Lord Farquaad, I accept. Nothing would make--
我来计划，我们明天结婚
Excellent! I'll start the plans, for tomorrow we wed!
不！我是说...
No! I mean, uh,
为什么要等？ 我们今天日落前结婚吧
why wait? Let's get married today before the sun sets.
着急了，是吧？你说得对
Oh, anxious, are we? You're right.
越早越好，有很多事要做
The sooner, the better. There's so much to do!
酒筵、乐队、客人名单
There's the caterer, the cake, the band, the guest list.
队长，列出客人名单！
Captain, round up some guests!
再见，妖怪
[ Fiona ] Fare-thee-well, ogre.
你在干什么？她要走了
Shrek, what are you doing? You're letting her get away.
- 那又怎么样？ - 有件事你应该知道
- Yeah? So what? - Shrek, there's something about her you don't know.
我昨晚跟她谈了，她...
Look, I talked to her last night. She's--
我知道你昨晚跟她谈了 你们是好朋友，是不是？
I know you talked to her last night. You're great pals, aren't ya?
如果你俩那么好 为什么不跟她回家？
Now, if you two are such good friends, why don't you follow her home?
史莱克，我想跟着你
Shrek, I-- I wanna go with you.
我说过，你不能跟我回家
I told you, didn't I? You're not coming home with me.
我自己住！我的沼泽地！ 我！不要外人，明白吗？
I live alone! My swamp! Me! Nobody else! Understand? Nobody!
特别不要无用、可怜 烦人、会说话的驴！
Especially useless, pathetic, annoying, talking donkeys!
- 但，我想... - 啊，你知道吗？
- But I thought-- - Yeah. You know what?
你的想法错了！
You thought wrong!
史莱克
Shrek.
∮ I heard there was a secret chord ∮
∮ That David played and it pleased the Lord ∮
∮ But you don't really care for music, do ya ∮
∮ It goes like this the fourth, the fifth ∮
∮ The minor fall the major lift ∮
∮ The baffled king composing hallelujah ∮
∮ Hallelujah ∮
∮ Baby, I've been here before ∮
∮ I know this room I've walked this floor∮
∮ I used to live alone before I knew you ∮
∮ I've seen your flag on the marble arch ∮
∮ But love is not a victory march ∮
∮ It's a cold and it's a broken hallelujah ∮
∮ Hallelujah ∮
∮ And all I ever learned from love ∮
∮ Is how to shoot at someone ∮
-∮ Who outdrew you ∮ - [ Moaning ]
∮ And it's not a cry you can hear at night ∮
∮ It's not somebody who's seen the light ∮
-∮ It's a cold and it's a broken hallelujah ∮
∮ Hallelujah ∮
∮ Hallelujah ∮∮
驴
Donkey∮
- 你在干什么？ - 我想你认识墙
- What are you doing∮ I would think, of all people, you would recognize a wall when you see one.
对，但墙应该围绕着 我的沼泽地，而不是通过
Well, yeah. But the wall's supposed to go around my swamp, not through it.
是这样的，这是你的一半 这是我的一半
It is around your half. See, that's your half, and this is my half.
一你的一半 一对，我帮你救了公主
Oh! Your half. Hmm. Yes, my half. I helped rescue the princess.
我干了一半的活儿 我得一半的战利品
I did half the work, I get half the booty.
把那个大石头给我 像你脑袋的那个
Now hand me that big old rock, the one that looks like your head.
- 后退 - 不，你后退
- Back off! - No, you back off.
- 这是我的沼泽地！ - 是我们的
- This is my swamp! - Our swamp.
- 松手！ - 你松手
- Let go, Donkey! - You let go.
- 蠢驴！ - 臭妖怪
- Stubborn jackass! - Smelly ogre.
好！
Fine!
回来，我还没说完呢
- Hey, come back here. I'm not through with you yet. - Well, I'm through with you.
- 我已经跟你说完了 - 你总是“我，我，我！”
Uh-uh. You know, with you it's always, ''Me, me, me!''
现在该轮到我了！ 闭上嘴听我说！
Well, guess what! Now it's my turn! So you just shut up and pay attention!
你对我很刻薄 侮辱我，我做的事你不领情
You are mean to me. You insult me and you don't appreciate anything that I do!
你总是摆布我，向外推我
You're always pushing me around or pushing me away.
是吗？如果我对你这么不好 你为什么要回来？
Oh, yeah? Well, if I treated you so bad, how come you came back?
因为我们是朋友！ 朋友互相原谅！
Because that's what friends do! They forgive each other!
你说得对，驴 我原谅你背叛了我！
Oh, yeah. You're right, Donkey. I forgive you... for stabbin' me in the back!
你把自己包了好几层 你害怕自己的感觉
Ohh! You're so wrapped up in layers, onion boy, you're afraid of your own feelings.
- 走开！ - 你又那么做了
- Go away! - There you are, doing it again just like you did to Fiona.
就像对菲奥娜一样 她喜欢你，也许甚至爱你
All she ever do was like you, maybe even love you.
爱我？她说我丑 是个可怕的动物
Love me? She said I was ugly, a hideous creature.
我听到你俩的谈话
I heard the two of you talking.
她不是说你，她是说别人
She wasn't talkin' about you. She was talkin' about, uh, somebody else.
她不是说我？ 那她说的是谁？
She wasn't talking about me? Well, then who was she talking about?
我不会说的 你不想听我说，对不对？
Uh-uh, no way. I ain't saying anything. You don't wanna listen to me. - Right? Right? - Donkey!
- 不！ - 好，对不起，行了吧？
- No! - Okay, look. I'm sorry, all right?
对不起 我是个大笨蛋，丑八怪
[ Sighs ] I'm sorry. I guess I am just a big, stupid, ugly ogre.
你能原谅我吗？
Can you forgive me?
朋友就该这样
Hey, that's what friends are for, right?
- 好，朋友？ - 朋友
Right. Friends? Friends.
那...菲奥娜说我什么了？
So, um, what did Fiona say about me?
你为什么问我？ 为什么不去问她？
What are you asking me for? Why don't you just go ask her?
婚礼！我们来不及了
The wedding! We'll never make it in time.
别怕，有志者，事竟成 我有办法
Ha-ha-ha! Never fear, for where there's a will, there's a way, and I have a way. [ Whistles ]
驴
- Donkey?
我想是我动物的魅力
I guess it's just my animal magnetism.
你，过来
[ Laughing ] Aw, come here, you.
别这样，没人喜欢拍驴屁的
All right, all right. Don't get all slobbery. No one likes a kiss ass.
好，上来抓紧
All right, hop on and hold on tight.
还没来得及安装安全带
I haven't had a chance to install the seat belts yet.
敬畏
People of DuLoc,
肃静
we gather here today...
...今天我们聚集在这里 来见证
to bear witness...
我们国王的结合...
- to the union... - Um-- - of our new king-- - Excuse me.
对不起 我们能不能跳到“我愿意”？
- Could we just skip ahead to the ''I do's''? - [ Chuckling ]
继续
Go on.
走吧，高兴点儿 需要你时我会吹口哨儿的
Go ahead, have some fun. If we need you, I'll whistle. How about that?
等一等！ 你要做那件事，对不对？
Shrek, wait, wait! Wait a minute!
你在说什么？
- You wanna do this right, don't you? - What are you talking about?
等待牧师说 “现在说否则永远保持沉默”
There's a line you gotta wait for. The preacher's gonna say, ''Speak now or forever hold your peace.''
- 这时你说“我反对” - 我没时间听你说！
- That's when you say, ''I object!'' - I don't have time for this!
- 听我说！你爱这个女人吗？ - 爱
Wait. What are you doing? Listen to me! - Look, you love this woman, don't you? - Yes.
- 你想拉她的手，取悦她吗？ - 对
- You wanna hold her? - Yes. - Please her? - Yes!
那么你得设法温柔点儿
y Then you got to, got to try a little tenderness yy
- 女人都喜欢这种浪漫！ - 这个家伙什么时候说这句？
- The chicks love that romantic crap! - All right! Cut it out.
- When does this guy say the line? - We gotta check it out.
- 我们得查一下儿 - 以我的权力...
- [ Donkey Grunting ] - And so, by the power vested in me,
- 你看到什么了？ - 全城的人都在
-[ Shrek ] What do you see? - The whole town's in there.
- 我宣布你们为夫妻... - 他们在圣坛上
- I now pronounce you husband and wife, - They're at the altar.
- 国王和王后 - 他已经说了！
- king and queen. - Mother Fletcher! He already said it.
看在圣彼得的份上！
- Oh, for the love of Pete! - [ Grunts ]
我反对！
I object!
他想干什么？
- Shrek? - [ Gasps ] Oh, now what does he want?
大家好 你们很愉快，是不是？
Hi, everyone. Havin' a good time, are ya?
- 我喜欢达罗克，很干净 - 你来这里干什么？
I love DuLoc, first of all. - Very clean. - What are you doing here?
没人想要你时还活着 已经够无礼的了
Really, it's rude enough being alive when no one wants you,
但不请自来参加婚礼...
-but showing up uninvited to a wedding-- -Fiona!
- 我要跟你谈谈 - 现在你想谈谈？
- I need to talk to you. - Oh, now you wanna talk?
有点儿晚了，请原谅...
It's a little late for that, so if you'll excuse me--
- 但你不能跟他结婚 - 为什么？
- But you can't marry him. - And why not?
因为他跟你结婚是为了当国王
Because-- Because he's just marrying you so he can be king.
令人气愤！别听他的
Outrageous! Fiona, don't listen to him.
- 他并不真正爱你 - 你懂爱吗？
- He's not your true love. - And what do you know about true love?
- 嗯，我...我是说 - 这真是有意思极了！
Well, I-- Uh-- - I mean-- - Oh, this is precious.
妖怪爱上了公主！
[ Chuckling ] The ogre has fallen in love with the princess!
庄严―笑
- Oh, good Lord. - [ Crowd Laughing ]
妖怪和公主！
An ogre and a princess! [ Laughing Continues ]
史莱克，这是真的吗？
Shrek, is this true?
谁管呢？多么荒唐！
Who cares? It's preposterous!
菲奥娜，亲爱的 吻完后就会永远幸福，吻我！
Fiona, my love, we're but a kiss away from our ''happily ever after.'' Now kiss me! Mmmm!
白天一个样，晚上一个样
''By night one way, by day another. ''
我想给你看看我晚上的模样
I wanted to show you before.
这说明了许多问题
Well, uh, that explains a lot.
真恶心！卫兵！卫兵！
[ Farquaad ] Ugh! It's disgusting! Guards! Guards!
我命令你们把他们赶走！
I order you to get that out of my sight now! Get them! - Get them both! - No, no!
这不会改变什么 这个婚姻仍算数，我是国王！
This hocus-pocus alters nothing. This marriage is binding, and that makes me king!
- 你瞧 - 不，放开我！
- See? See? - No, let go of me! Shrek!
- 别站在那里 - 滚出去！菲奥娜！
- No! - [ Farquaad ] Don't just stand there,you morons. Get out of my way! Fiona!
我要让你后悔我们见面 祈求让你死得痛快！
I'll make you regret the day we met. I'll see you drawn and quartered!
- You'll beg for death to save you! - No! Shrek!
至于你，我的妻子
- And as for you, my wife, - Fiona!
我要把你关进那个塔里 让你永无天日
I'll have you locked back in that tower for the rest of your days!
我是国王！我要下命令！ 我要尽善尽美！我要...
- I am king! - [ Whistles ] I will have order! I will have perfection! I will have--
不准动，我有龙 我会毫不犹豫使用他的
- Aah! - All right. Nobody move. I got a dragon here, and I'm not afraid to use it.
我是头发怒的驴！
-[ Dragon Roars ] - I'm a donkey on the edge!
名人的婚姻，从没持久过
Celebrity marriages. They never last, do they?
去啊，史莱克
Go ahead, Shrek.
- 菲奥娜？ - 什么，史莱克？
Uh, Fiona? Yes, Shrek?
- 我爱你 - 真的？
I-- I love you. Really?
- 真的，真的 - 我也爱你
Really, really. I love you too.
直到你找到真正爱的初吻 变成真正爱的模样...
''Until you find true love's first kiss...  and then take love's true form. ''
菲奥娜
Fiona?
Fiona.
- 你没事儿吧？ - 嗯，没事儿
Are you all right? Well, yes.
但我不明白，我应该漂亮
But I don't understand. I'm supposed to be beautiful.
你是很漂亮
But you are beautiful.
我希望是个幸福的结局
I was hoping this would be a happy ending.
∮ I thought love was only true in fairy tales ∮
∮ Meant for someone else but not for me ∮
∮ Love was out to get me ∮
∮ That's the way it seemed ∮
∮ Disappointment haunted all my dreams ∮
∮ And then I saw her face ∮
∮ Now I'm a believer∮
∮ And not a trace ∮
∮ Of doubt in my mind ∮
-∮ I'm in love ∮ -∮ Ooh-ahh ∮
∮ I'm a believer I couldn't leave her∮
∮ If I tried ∮
上帝保佑，每一个人
God bless us, every one.
来，大家一起唱！
Come on,y'all! ∮ Then I saw her face ∮ Ha-ha!
y Now I'm a believer y Listen!
∮ Not a trace ∮
∮ Of doubt in my mind ∮
y I'm in love Ooh-ahh y
y I'm a believer I couldn't leave her if I tried y
y Then I saw her face y
y Now I'm a believer y Hey!
∮ Not a trace ∮ Uhh! Yeah.
再来一次！
∮ Of doubt in my mind ∮ One more time!
y I'm in love I'm a believer y
Come on!
y I believe, I believe I believe, I believe y
y I believe, I believe I believe, I believe, I believe, hey y
你们都跟我一起唱！
Y'all sing it with me! ∮ I ∮
∮ Believe ∮
后面的人！
y I believe y People in the back! - y I believe y -∮ I'm a believer∮
∮ I believe ∮
他们后来一起丑陋地生活 “完”
∮ I believe ∮ ∮ I believe ∮∮
这真有趣！ 我喘不过气了，我喘不过气了
Oh, that's funny. Oh. Oh. I can't breathe. I can't breathe.
∮ I believe in self-assertion ∮
∮ Destiny or a slight diversion ∮
∮ Now it seems I've got my head on straight ∮
∮ I'm a freak an apparition ∮
∮ Seems I've made the right decision ∮
∮ To try to turn back now it might be too late ∮
-∮ I want to stay home today ∮ -∮ Don't wanna go out ∮
-∮ If anyone comes to play ∮ -∮ Gonna get thrown out ∮
-∮ I wanna stay home today ∮ -∮ Don't want no company ∮
∮ No way ∮
∮ Yeah,yeah,yeah ∮
∮ I wanna be a millionaire someday ∮
∮ But know what it feels like to give it away ∮
∮ Watch me march to the beat of my own drum ∮
∮ And it's off to the moon and then back again ∮
∮ Same old day Same situation ∮
∮ My happiness rears back as if to say ∮
-∮ I wanna stay home today ∮ -∮ Don't wanna go out ∮
-∮ If anyone comes my way ∮ -∮ Gonna get thrown out ∮
-∮ I wanna stay home today ∮ -∮ Don't want no company ∮
∮ No way ∮
∮ Yeah,yeah,yeah ∮
∮ I wanna stay home stay home, stay home ∮
-∮ I wanna stay home today ∮ -∮ Don't wanna go out ∮
-∮ If anyone comes to play ∮ -∮ Gonna get thrown out ∮
∮ I wanna stay home today ∮
∮ Don't want no company No way ∮
∮ Yeah,yeah,yeah ∮∮
∮ I get such a thrill when you look in my eyes ∮
∮ My heart skips a beat Girl, I feel so alive ∮
∮ Please tell me, baby if all this is true ∮
∮'Cause deep down inside all I wanted was you ∮
∮ Oh-oh-oh Makes me wanna dance ∮
∮ Oh-oh-oh It's a new romance ∮
∮ Oh-oh-oh I look into your eyes ∮
∮ Oh-oh-oh The best years of our lives ∮
∮ When we first met I could hardly believe ∮
∮ The things that would happen and we could achieve ∮
∮ So let's be together for all of our time ∮
∮ Oh, girl, I'm so thankful that you are still mine ∮
∮ You always consider me like an ugly duckling ∮
∮ And treat me like a Nostradamus was why I had to get my shine on ∮
∮ I break a little something to keep my mind on ∮
∮'Cause you had my mind gone Eh-eh, eh-eh, eh-eh ∮
∮ Turn the lights on, Come on, baby Let's just rewind the song ∮
∮'Cause all I want to do is make the rest years the best years ∮
∮ All night long ∮
-∮ Oh-oh-oh, makes me wanna dance ∮ -∮ Makes me wanna dance ∮
-∮ Oh-oh-oh, it's a new romance ∮ -∮ It's a new romance ∮
-∮ Oh-oh-oh, I look into your eyes ∮ -∮ Oh,yeah,yeah ∮
-∮ Look into your eyes ∮ -∮ Oh-oh-oh ∮
-∮ The best years of our lives ∮ -∮ Yeah,yeah,yeah,yeah ∮
-∮ Oh-oh-oh, makes me wanna dance ∮ -∮ Whoa-oh-oh, dance,yeah ∮
∮ Oh-oh-oh It's a new romance ∮
-∮ Oh-oh-oh, I look into your eyes ∮ -∮ Look into your eyes,yeah ∮
∮ Oh-oh-oh The best years of our lives ∮∮
∮ Everything looks bright ∮
∮ Standing in your light ∮
∮ Everything feels right ∮
∮ What's left is out of sight ∮
∮ What's a girl to do I'm telling you You're on my mind ∮
∮ I wanna be with you ∮
∮'Cause when you're standin'next to me ∮
∮ It's like wow ∮
∮ And all your kisses seem to set me free ∮
∮ And when we touch it's such a rush I can't get enough ∮
∮ It's like-- It's like Ooh-ooh ∮
∮ Hey, what ∮
∮ It's like wow Ooh-ooh, hey ∮
∮ Hey,yeah It's like wow ∮
∮ Everything is looking right now, right now ∮
-∮ It's like wow ∮ -∮ And I got this feeling ∮
∮ This feeling it's just like wow ∮
∮ It's just like wow ∮
- You are all I'm thinking of. -∮ Like wow ∮
∮ Everything feels right Everything feels right ∮
-∮ Like wow ∮ -∮ Everything looks bright ∮
All my senses are right.
-∮ Like wow ∮ -∮ Everything feels right ∮
∮ Baby, baby, baby the way I'm feeling you ∮
∮ Is like wow ∮∮
∮ There is something that I see ∮
∮ In the way you look at me ∮
∮ There's a smile There's a truth ∮
∮ In your eyes ∮
∮ What an unexpected way ∮
∮ On this unexpected day ∮
∮ Could it be ∮
∮ This is where I belong ∮
∮ It is you I have loved ∮
∮ All along ∮
∮ There's no more mystery ∮
∮ It is finally clear to me ∮
∮ You're the home my heart's searched for∮
∮ So long ∮
∮ It is you I have loved ∮
∮ All along ∮
∮ Whoa, over and over∮
∮ I'm filled with emotion ∮
∮ As I look ∮
∮ Into your perfect face ∮∮